You said you don't uh treat obese guys.
Do they need to reach a certain um body
mass index before you will treat them?
And if
>> yeah,
>> will will putting them on testosterone
not help them lose weight or put in the
effort to do it?
>> Good question. So, a couple of different
things to address. First of all, I
didn't say I don't treat obese. I said
morbidly obese. Okay. Um, unfortunately,
most of America is obese. Okay? So, if I
didn't treat obesity, I I wouldn't
wouldn't be here. Um, morbidly obese.
Um, and when I say treat, I was
referring specifically to testosterone.
I do treat anyone and everyone according
to what I feel is going to benefit that
individual in the short term. Because if
I want to give you a long-term
treatment, the first thing that I have
to do responsibly and ethically, I owe
you the opportunity to assess what's
going on and tell you, look, I feel that
ultimately you're going to need this,
but before we get there, the current
risks outweigh the benefits. Therefore,
let's bring you into a position where we
can start doing this safely. If you take
a man who is 6 foot, 300 lb, okay, that
is morbidly obese. That is somebody who
is far more likely to die than the
average person. Okay? He's about 100
pounds more than someone his size should
be. That's not somebody who's got a BMI
of, you know, 30 or 29. That's somebody
who's got a BMI of like north of 35,
right? Then you couple that with the
fact that I can almost bet my left arm
that he has obstructive sleep apnea due
to obesity. I could also bet you that
he's got some form of metabolic syndrome
because let's face it, the lifestyle
that got him to that body weight is
probably not the healthiest lifestyle.
So, he's not as active. He's seditary.
He's got a terrible diet. He doesn't
sleep well. He may be a smoker, maybe
not. He's probably stressed. Probably
got some form of depression. All right?
Because you can't tell me you're walking
around 100 pounds overweight and you're
happy as can be. So at the end of the
day when you look at the picture of the
whole person and you say to yourself if
I put this man on testosterone today
first his likelihood of dying not
because of testosterone just in general
right is higher significantly than an
average guy. That puts me under scrutiny
and under potential risk for liability
which I'm not willing to accept anymore
um because it's just it's just
unfortunately that's just the way the
industry is right now. Secondly, the
initial spike of aldoststerone
uh which may increase you know
hypervalmic hypertension risk for a
period of months uh coupled with what we
already determined to be a bad diet
which is why he's obese right um that is
a risk in and of itself that's a
cardiovascular risk and I'm not willing
to increase his cardiovascular risk
which is already present. So there's a
lot of factors playing into this where
I'm not going to put a band-aid on a
broken leg. We need to fix the
underlying issue here. Will testosterone
ultimately help this man? Sure. Is he
ready for testosterone today? No. The
risks are too great, both legally and
medically. So, what we need to do is we
need to maybe get this guy on a meal
plan. We need to get this guy on an
exercise plan. We need to get this guy
on a GLP1 for weight loss. And a lot of
these guys who are receptive to these
ideas do come back to us in three, four,
five, six months and they're down 60 and
70 pounds and now we initiate TRT. A lot
of these guys say, "No, I just want
TRT." And they go about their way. And
guess what? 6 months later, we may see
them again and now they're 320 lbs.
They're going in the wrong direction
because they refused to accept
responsibility for what brought them
here and they just wanted a medication
rather than actually putting in the
effort. I am not going to reward
self-destructive behavior
with pharmarmacology. I'm going to
reward productive behavior and an
initiative and accountability with
assistance and guidance and maybe a
little bit of medication. So, it's more
so a decision of look, we're very busy.
We have more patience than time and
we're very selective in helping those
who want to help. And the way to prove
that you want to help is to show me that
you're willing to help yourself. Because
if I want you to succeed more than you
want to succeed, we have a problem.